#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**



PERSONAL DETAILS - RAHUL J ADESARA

Residential Address: C-206, Royal Residency, S.G. Highway,

Ahmedabad - 382481.

Mobile: +91 7990 549 473

E-mail: adesararahul@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 5<sup>th</sup> August, 1992

Nationality: Indian

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Thorough professional, with high calibre, work orientation, and ability to handle multiple functions and activities in a high pressure environment due to inherent ability to identify and prioritize tasks at hand. Ability to motivate and keep team members focused. Excellent man-management, time management, and leadership skills. Multilingual with proficiency in English, Hindi, Gujarati To expand skills and experience within the Finance and Costing department of an international or MNC groups of companies or association. Always want to learn more and more. Work is my heart.

# **EDUCATION / QUALIFICATION HISTORY**

Jun 2010 – Aug 2012 Institute Of Chartered Accountants Of

**India**, Ahmedabad, GUJARAT

Inter in Chartered Accountancy (Inter CA)

May 2010 – May 2013 S.M. Patel Institute Of Commerce

(**Gujarat University**, Ahmedabad,

GUJARAT)

Bachelor of Commerce with Accountancy

Specialist (B. Com)

May 2008 – May 2010 Gujarat Higher Secondary Board,

Ahmedabad, GUJARAT

High School Certificate equivalent

#### **WORK PERFORMANCE - Responsibilities**

- Weekly report stating that the summary of Income and detailed expenses department wise, market wise and brand wise.
- Monthly Consumption report against sales
- Budget preparation of Revenue, Expenses and Capex
- MIRO Booking, i.e. Service Goods Receipt Note (GRN) entries in SAP for accounting. GL scrutinizing. Cost centre to cost centre transfer expenses.
   Arrange and handle of expenses for the accounting purpose.
- Commercial activities like to give the Product Price, Final Pricing And Analysis (FP & A) work, report to the management regarding the same.
- Cash Flow Statement preparation.
- Weekly yield report Product wise and also Segment wise, i.e. OSD (Tablet mfg.), Injections, Vaccine, Syrup...etc
- Monthly Profit and Loss account Market wise (i.e. US Market, ROW Market...etc), Brand wise.
- Weekly report of expenses is spent UID wise. i.e. Actual Variable expense, Allocation and Fixed expenses against the Budget of specific UID. Comparison of Actual Vs. Budget.
- Monthly report of Budget vs. Plan/Forecast vs. Actual Income as well as expenses. Also stating the remarks, if any, of deviation from Plan or Budget.
- Calculating the costing of the products which are going to be launched.
  Give the reply to query raised by FP & A team.
- Provide the Costing calculation for External / Internal project of BA/BE studies perform by the CRO Department (Clinical Research Organisation).

- Costing of Clinical trials and Pre-clinical Study which are to be performed by the CRO team.
- Controlling the above mentioned project. i.e Expenses controlling,
  Authorisation of expenses.
- Loan licensing work. Reconciliation of all LL parties with books of account maintained by us. Raising Debit or Credit note to the LL party if any difference in Reco-Statement.
- Inventory provision on monthly basis with remarks from Quality Department, SCM Department, Production Department, Store Department... etc.
- COPA work done on quarterly basis. Scrutinized the G/L and Cost centre to do the easy and best way for COPA
- Helping to develop the COPA related assessment cycle, Cost centre framework.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

July 2019 to Till Date

# **Luthra Group LLP (Surat)**

Deputy Finance Manager

Reporting to General Finance - MIS Manager

Responsibilities and achievements:

- All Financial activities at corporate management level
- Preparation and analysis of Cost Sheet plant wise (Total 7 plants pan of India)
- WBS management
- Provide the guidance to the Account and Finance team related to SAP and MIS
- · Monthly forecasting report Plant wise.
- · Cash flow preparation and analysis
- Inventory analysis
- Preparation of MIS Report for production along with proper

justification notes

- Monthly analysis of Budget Vs. Budget For Actual Vs. Actual
- PPV Report on monthly basis (Purchase Price Variance)
- Preparation of Revenue & CAPEX Budget
- Budget Analysis and management, along with yearly preparation of Budget (Capex as well as Revenue and Expense Budget)
- Monthly and Weekly MIS presentation to the Management
- Analysis of Materials movements.

# **Arvind Limited (Ahmedabad)**

Commercial Finance Manager

Reporting to Chief Finance - MIS Manager

Responsibilities and achievements:

- SAP Implementation (MM Module and FICO Module) at Plant
- All Commercial activities handle
- Financial activities at Plant
- Sales Order wise costing upload in SAP
- WBS management
- Material Management
- Monthly forecasting report market wise. i.e Domestic and **Export**
- Inventory analysis
- Preparation of MIS Report for production along with proper justification notes
- Monthly analysis of budget vs. forecasting
- PPV Report on monthly basis (Purchase Price Variance)
- Preparation of Revenue & CAPEX Budget
- Budget Analysis and management
- Monthly and Bi-Weekly MIS preparation
- Consumption of materials.

Aug 2018 To July 2019 March 2018 To July 2018

### **Vadilal Industry Limited (Ahmedabad)**

Costing & MIS (Budget) Executive

Reporting to SR. Manager

#### Responsibilities and achievements:

- Cost Management and Analysis
- Derive the Actual cost of products and comparison between standard costs with actual one.
- Monthly forecasting report
- Monthly MIS Report
- Preparation of MIS Report for production along with proper justification notes
- Monthly analysis of budget vs. forecasting
- Preparing Factory wise Plan monthly
- Derive the cost of new launching product as per requirement of FP & A team
- Preparing & Evaluation of Daily productivity Report each factory wise
- PPV Report on monthly basis (Purchase Price Variance)
- Preparation of Yield Report on monthly basis
- Various types of Cost Evaluation projects
- Preparation of Revenue & CAPEX Budget

May 2017 To Feb 2018

# Cadila Pharmaceutical Limited (Ahmedabad)

Finance Controller

Reporting to AVP (Asst. Vice President- Finance)

#### Responsibilities and achievements:

- SAP Accounting entries
- MIRO Booking, i.e. Goods Receipt Note (GRN) entries in SAP
- Monthly forecasting (plan) report of Expenses and Income department wise
- Finalisation of Financial Statements

- Prepare the cost sheet of Project and new product to be studied in R & D.
- Also preparing the costing for External Testing / study done by R & D department and prepared for the final quotation to the External vendor.
- Preparation of MIS Report for production along with proper justification notes
- Vendor reconciliation, Provision Liability Report, Creditors
  Report
- Monthly analysis of budget vs. Forecasting
- Derive the cost of new launching product as per requirement of FP & A team
- COPA rectification, G/L Scrutinize, Cost center scrutinize,
  Internal Order wise cost maintained.
- Controlling the Budget of Research And Development department
- Preparing & Evaluation of productivity Report
- Preparing Market wise Profit and Loss Account monthly basis. Analysis of the P&L and give the justification to the management after Marketing analysis.
- Preparation of Factory budgets department wise i.e.
  Revenue and CAPEX budget
- Support to the management for preparing an action plan to achieve the ultimate goal of the organization
- Working and participating to the CAPEX applications team, preparation and validation of costs and benefits
   (Opportunity Cost), manage subsequent spend,...etc
- Identify hidden costs and lack of efficiency, e.g. Idle man and labour hours due to lack of man-power, unavailability of electricity, breakdown in machinery.
- Prepared the Decision making reports to the management for Job working or In-house Production
- COPA related work, Cost centre wise bifurcation of Expense

# Sep 2015 To Apr 2017

# **Mylan Laboratories Limited (Ahmedabad)**

Costing - Finance (MIS) Analyst

Reporting to Sr. General Manager - Finance

#### Responsibilities and achievements:

- Cost Management and Analysis
- Derive the Actual cost of products and comparison between standard costs with actual one.
- Monthly forecasting report
- KPI Report of R & D , Monthly
- Preparation of MIS Report for production along with proper justification notes
- Monthly analysis of budget vs. forecasting
- Preparing Factory wise Plan monthly
- Derive the cost of new launching product as per requirement of FP & A team
- Control the Budget of Research And Development department
- Preparing & Evaluation of Daily productivity Report each factory wise
- PPV Report on monthly basis
- Preparation of Yield Report on monthly basis
- Preparation of Revenue Budget (Research & Development department and DRA Department)
- All service related invoice authorisation
- I have handle costing for three plants, i.e. Ahmedabad (SEZ), Sarigam (EOU-1), Sarigam (EOU-2), Daman

# November 2014 To Aug

2015

# **Amrapali Fincap Limited (Amrapali Group)**

Ahmedabad GUJARAT

Finance And Tax Executive

Reporting to Managing Director

#### Responsibilities and achievements:

- Cost Management and Analysis
- Monthly Budget Vs. forecasting report

•	Control the Account department of three companies for
	MIS preparation

Analysis of Under absorption and Over absorption expenses

Handling the scrutiny department of Income Tax

August 2012

#### **Viva Overseas (Viva Group)**

To Oct 2014

Ahmedabad GUJARAT

Account - Finance Executive cum Manager

#### Responsibilities and achievements:

Handle the whole Account department of three companies
 Virtual Link

Viva Overseas

Value Export

• Income Tax Department, TDS work, Scrutiny handling work

#### **OTHER SKILLS AND CERTIFICATES**

#### **Computer Skills:**

- I can work faster than other with much more accuracy.
- Habit of learning more & more in terms of technically.
- Specialised in Microsoft Office(Word, Excel, Power Point, Office Outlook)
- SAP Material Module, Costing Module, Finance Module
- **BI BO** Operation (Web intelligence), BPC Analysis tools (SAP)
- Tally ERP 9, Miracle (Accounting Software), Easy Office (Taxation Software) Tech Excel (Online Accounting – Stock Exchange Software) – Intermediate

# Language Skills:

- Gujarati (Native Tongue)
- Hindi (reading, writing and speaking skills) National Language
- English (reading, writing and speaking skills)
- Marathi (Understanding skills only)

#### Other Certification:

- Chhatrapati Shivaji Award General Knowledge.
- Intermediary Certificate of Drawing 2007.
- CII Certificate in Business Analyst
- Certificate of Asia Pacific Completion In Science And Technology

#### PERSONAL COMPETENCIES

- Ability to work in a fast-paced environment to set deadlines.
- Excellent oral and written correspondence with an exceptional attention to detail.
- Highly organised with a creative flair for project work.
- Enthusiastic self-starter who contributes well to the team.
- Hard worker without hesitation of time.
- To do the work faster than other with accuracy.
- The main reason to change the job is that my ultimate goal is to play my role in to an international group.

#### **INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES**

 Watching Tennis, Cricket, Music, Planning and Leading the team work together.

I hereby conclude that, the information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. Hope that positive reply.

Place:-Surat

(Rahul J Adesara)